101號模態遭入侵/非法用戶
-Seq 我進來了 -艦長
-Seq, I'm in. -Captain.
你是對的
You were right.
追蹤程式開始運行
天窗的確是扇窗格
The skylight was a window pane.
干擾非常嚴重
I've got serious interference.
奇怪 這像是某種模態
Weird. It's some kind of Modal.
看起來像是舊編碼
Looks like old code.
有種很熟悉的感覺
It feels really familiar.
標記一下 我發信號請求支援
Drop a pin. I'll signal for backup.
我要去確認一下 Bugs
I'm gonna check it out. Bugs?
如果將軍發現了我們一直在盲目瞎找……
If the general finds out we've been fishing...
瞄一眼沒事的
A quick peek can't hurt.
你聽到了嗎
Did you hear that?
壞了 我想我們的信號被追蹤了
Shit. I think our signal was traced.
Bugs 這感覺像個陷阱
Bugs, this feels like a trap.
Bugs
Bugs!
別動 不許動
Freeze!Do not move!
我們會開槍的
We will shoot!
慢慢地 把手舉起來
Very slowly, raise your hands.
又來這套……
Here we go.
嘿 你要去哪裡
Hey, where are you going?
我警告過你了 中尉
You were warned, Lieutenant.
我想我們對付得了一個小姑娘
I think we can handle one little girl.
你在浪費時間
You're wasting your time!
我的人現在正帶她下來
My men are bringing her down now.
不 中尉
No, Lieutenant,
你的人已經死了
your men are already dead.
Seq 你在嗎
Seq, you with me?
這個舊編碼在不斷崩潰
This old code keeps crashing.
你的投影故障了 切換成音訊吧
Your projection's breaking up. Switch to audio.
Bugs 這完全違反了
Bugs, this is a direct violation
將軍的規定
of the general's protocols.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
但是 這裡事有蹊蹺
But something is happening here.
非常重要的事情
Something important.
哦 靠
Oh, fuck.
我們知道接下來會發生什麼
We know what happens next.
她打爆他們
She kicks their ass.
現在她要打電話
Now she makes a call.
線路被追蹤了
The line was traced.
然後... 她就開始逃命了
And then... Then she runs for her life.
有特工嗎
Are there any agents?
我們都知道這個故事
We know this story.
一切就是這樣開始的
This is how it all began.
該死的
God damn it.
這就是他開始的地方
This is where he began.
Modal在程式設計中是彈出式對話方塊
你覺得它是在循環 還是一個迴圈機
You're thinking this Modal is a loop? Or a treadmill?
程式序列演化成這樣 要做什麼
Some sort of sequencer evolving a program to do what?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我會搞清楚的
But I'm going to find out.
好吧
All right.
很似曾相識 但是顯然都是錯的
So deja vu and yet it's obviously all wrong.
舊編碼怎翻出新花樣
Why use old code to mirror something new?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果那是Trinity的話
If that's supposed to be Trinity,
就不是這結果
that's not what happens.
也許這不是那個故事
Maybe this isn't the story we think it is.
Bugs 你必須離開這裡了
Bugs, you have to get out of here.
這肯定是個陷阱
It's gotta be a trap.
壞了
Shit.
嗯...
Uh...
你們繼續吧
You all carry on.
當我沒來過
As you were.
我就……
I'm just gonna...
不打攪各位了
see myself out.
殺了她
Kill her.
-為什麼救我 -你先說
-Why did you save me? -You first.
你是誰 你從哪裡來
Who are you? Where did you come from?
好吧
Okay.
我叫 Bugs
My name is Bugs.
賓尼兔全名叫 Bugs Bunny
跟 賓尼兔 同名
As in "Bunny"
竊聽器的俗稱
And tech that listens.
你知道這裡是一個模態嗎
Do you know this is a Modal?
什麼是模態
What's a Modal?
一種用於演化程式的類比框架
It's a simulation used to evolve programs.
你明白你是一個……
Do you understand that you are...
有知覺的電子體
digital sentience?
我知道我是什麼
I know what I am.
我也知道我的工作
Just like I know my job
就是追捕和消滅合成體
is to hunt down and destroy synthients.
像你這樣的
Like you.
然而...
And yet...
還是落到這田地
Here we are.
這步田地
其他特工不知道這個房間嗎
The other agents don't know about this room?
你怎麼找到的
How'd you find it?
從來沒有人來過鑰匙店
No one was ever in the key shop,
所以我就進來看看
so I started looking.
看的越多 發現的越多
More you looked, the more you found.
我的人生也是這樣
Story of my life.
怎麼了
What?
我覺得我好像認識這個房間
I feel like I know this room.
天啊
Holy shit.
這是他的公寓
This is his apartment.
你是說Thomas Anderson的
You mean Thomas Anderson's?
到處都找過了 他根本不存在
I searched everywhere. He doesn't exist.
他很久以前就不再是Thomas了
He stopped being Thomas a long time ago,
但也許你知道他的真名
but maybe you know him by his real name.
Neo
Neo.
你真知道
You do.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
嗯...
Uh...
真不敢相信 這麼多年過去了
I can't believe this, after all these years.
你看 大多數人都認為Neo死了
You see, most people think that Neo is dead.
但我知道他沒死
But I know he's not.
因為我見過他
Because I've seen him.
在哪裡
Where?
有點難解釋 但是...
It's not something I can explain easily, but...
但是當時他有看到我
But the moment he looked at me,
我感覺到了...
I felt something...
我的意志被解鎖了一般
unlock my mind.
好吧
Okay.
我跟你有類似經歷
Something like that happened to me.
我看到了一些圖案...
I saw this pattern...
到處都是
and it was everywhere.
我們看不到 但我們都被困在一個
We can't see it, but we're all trapped inside
奇怪的 不斷重複的循環裡
these strange, repeating loops.
不知為何我能在鏡子裡看到
Somehow I saw it in the mirror.
只是一閃而過 但就像你說的
Just a flicker, but it was like you said.
我突然明白了
And suddenly I understood.
這不是真實的世界
This is not the real world.
這是第一次 我感到真正的使命
For the first time, I felt real purpose.
我知道我是誰
I knew who I was
還有我必須做的事
and what I had to do.
你是誰
Who are you?
你必須做什麼
What do you have to do?
我是...
I am...
Morpheus
Morpheus.
我必須找到Neo
And I have to find Neo.
Morpheus
Morpheus.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
哦 我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我得帶你離開這裡
I have to get you out of here.
我要找出誰建造了這個模態
I need to figure out who built this Modal.
好 跟我來
Okay, come with me.
你必須準備好離開 你必須真的準備好
You have to be ready to leave. You have to be really ready.
如果你沒準備好
And if you're not,
如果你覺得這裡才是你該待的地方
if you think that this is where you belong...
你覺得我有得選
You call this a choice?
哦 老實講 當初有人給我這藥丸的時候
Oh, honestly, when somebody offered me these things,
我不信這是二進位的世界
I went off on binary conceptions of the world
我說我沒辦法吞下
and said there was no way I was swallowing
這個否定我人生的藥丸
some symbolic reduction of my life.
那個拿藥丸的女人笑了
And the woman with the pills laughed
因為我沒抓住重點
'cause I was missing the point.
什麼重點
What point?
有選擇是一種錯覺
The choice is an illusion.
你已經知道了你必須做什麼
You already know what you have to do.
追求真相
Truth.
好
Okay.
有一座古老建築
There's an old building
有天窗 還有很多樓梯
with a skylight and lots of stairs.
拉法葉酒店
The Lafayette.
四個後門中的一個通向那裡
One of the four back doors leads there.
哦
Oh.
不要抗拒  哇 發生什麼事了
Don't fight it. Whoa, what's happening?
保持呼吸
Keep breathing.
意識抽取效果都差不多
Extraction works pretty much the same
不管是對人類還是程式
for humans and programs.
哎喲
Ouch.
啊
Ah.
好啊
Okay.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
我從來沒戴過其他眼鏡
I've never worn different glasses before.
是 很帥 哪扇門
Yeah, looks good. Which door?
應該是這... 好的
It's gotta be... Okay.
White特工
Agent White.
Smith特工
Agent Smith?
走
Go!
Seq.你聽的到我說話嗎
Seq! Can you hear me?
Bugs 我以為你失聯了
Bugs! I thought I lost you.
你能帶我們去窗格嘛
Can you get us to the window pane?
Bugs Bugs 他是個特工
Bugs! Bugs! He's an agent!
那扇窗 快走
That window! Go hard!
超凡互動性遊戲設計獎
怎麼回...
What the...
什麼鬼
What the hell?
出什麼事了
Something wrong?
嗯 程式有點小崩潰
Uh... Just a little crash.
早上好 Bobbi  早上好 夥計
Morning, Bobbi. Morning, dude.
真是美好的一天 我說得對嗎
What a beautiful day to be alive. Am I right?
-什麼情況 -他把什麼東西弄丟了
-Problemo? -He lost something.
這是舊的Matrix編碼嗎
Is this old Matrix code?
一個小小的模態試驗
A little Modal experiment.
給 Binary 的嗎
For Binary?
-我需要一杯咖啡  -咖啡 好的 馬上來
-I need a coffee. -Coffee. Yes, stat!
我去買
I'm buying.
我不想對你拍馬屁
I'm not trying to blow smoke up your ass,
但是我第一次玩三部曲的時候 我被震撼了
but the first time I played the trilogy, I was shook.
自由意志和命運之間的悖論
The paradox between free will and destiny.
我們只是按照演算法
Are we all just algorithms
做我們要做的事
doing what we're supposed to do
還是我們能逃脫程式控制
or can we escape our programming?
天才 隱藏在遊戲中 順便一說
Genius, inside the context of the game, BT dubs.
嘿 它完全佔據了我全部生活
Hey, did I tell you it took over my life?
沒錯 我七年級都沒畢業
Yeah. I failed the seventh grade.
你的遊戲差點毀了我
Your game almost ruined me.
-你已經說過 -聊到這了
-So you've said. -Yet here we are.
你告訴我 Anderson先生
You tell me, Mr. Anderson,
這是自由意志
is it free will
還是命運
or destiny?
哦 耶
Oh, yeah.
她可來了
There she is.
極品美魔女
Total f-ing MILF.
別瞪我 聽著 我很抱歉
Daggers. Look, I'm sorry.
我是個書呆子 我是機械養大的
I'm a geek. I was raised by machines.
也許你該走了
Maybe you should go.
別 求你 我保證 好好表現
No, please. I... I promise, best self.
好好表現
Best self.
好的
Sure.
你和她搭訕過嗎
You ever talk to her?
跟你說
Tell you what.
為了你為我所做的一切 這事包在我身上了
For all you've done for me, let me do this for you.
Jude 不 停下來
Jude, no. Stop.
-對不起 打擾一下 -謝謝
-Excuse me. Excuse me. -Thanks.
你好...
Hi. Um...
我知道這有點冒昧
I know this is all a bit extemporaneous.
我是Jude Gallagher
I'm Jude Gallagher.
我在一家遊戲公司工作 叫Deus Machina
I work for a game company called Deus Machina.
嗨 Jude 我是Tiffany
Hi, Jude, I'm Tiffany.
Tiffany 哇喔 沒想到你叫這名字
Tiffany. Wow. Didn't see that coming.
Audrey Hepburn主演過《Tiffany的早餐》
-我媽媽愛Audrey Hepburn -Jude
-Mom loved Audrey Hepburn. -Jude.
哦 這是我非常好的朋友 Thomas Anderson
Oh, and this is my very good friend, Thomas Anderson.
他是個如假包換的大名人
He is a bona fide famous person
大多數人認為他是
and considered by most to be
我們這一代中最偉大的遊戲設計師
the greatest game designer of our generation.
我很抱歉他這樣
I'm sorry about this.
-Jude... -和她談談
-Jude... -Just talk to her.
嗨 Thomas 大家都叫我 Tiff
Hi, Thomas. Everyone calls me "Tiff"
你好
Hi.
我們在哪裡見過嗎
Have we met?
嗯 我們都常來這裡
Uh, we both come here.
-我可以吃你的麵包嗎  -嘿
-Can I have your morning bun? -Hey!
你是想泡我媽嗎
Are you trying to ball my mom or what?
Brandon
Brandon!
我能吃一口嗎
Can I have one bite?
寶貝 發生什麼事 我們要遲到了
Babe! What's going on? We're gonna be late.
這是我丈夫 Chad
This is my husband, Chad.
很高興認識你  嘿
-Nice to meet you. -Hey.
寶貝 我們帶 Callie 去練習了
Babe, we gotta get Callie to practice.
好的  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
來吧孩子們 我們走了
Come on, kids. Let's move out.
101號模態未找到
什麼
What?
101號模態檔已清除
很抱歉 嗯 老闆叫你
Sorry. Uh, it's the boss.
幾十億人 他們都過得...
"Billions of people just living out their lives...
渾渾噩噩
oblivious"
我一直很喜歡這句臺詞
I always loved that line.
你寫的 是嗎
You wrote that one, yeah?
每次我站在這裡
Every time I stand here,
我想 老.天.爺.啊
I mean, OMG.
太完美了 一定是假的
It's so perfect, it's gotta be fake.
對吧
Right?
是啊
Yeah.
當然
Sure.
請坐
Have a seat.
抽煙嗎
Smoke?
我以為你戒煙了
I thought you quit.
我不把它當嗜好了
I quit calling it a habit.
只是有點罪惡感
Now it's just a guilty pleasure.
哦 也許我能幫幫你
Oh. Maybe I can make this easy for you.
我知道 Binary 的開發有點超出預算
I know Binary is over budget.
這不是 Binary 的事 Tom 比這嚴重的多
This is not about Binary, Tom. It's bigger than that.
這關乎你我的未來
This is about our future,
這就很棘手了 考慮到我們的過去
which is a sticky subject, given our past.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
治療進行的怎麼樣了
How's the therapy?
很好
Good.
沒什麼
Any...
小插曲嗎
episodes?
沒有
No.
太好了
That's terrific.
聽著 Tom 我知道我們總是有分歧
Look, Tom, I know we've always had our differences.
我們第一次見面 你怎麼形容的
What did you say about our first meeting?
我們的化學反應就像FBI審訊一樣
We had all the chemistry of an FBI interrogation.
但是看看這裡
But look at this place.
我們做到了
We did this.
一起做到的
Together.
是啊
Yeah.
現在又怎樣了
Now what?
情況變了 市場不景氣
Things have changed. The market's tough.
我相信你能理解為什麼我們敬愛的
I'm sure you can understand why our beloved
母公司華納兄弟
parent company, Warner Bros.,
決定製作三部曲的續集
has decided to make a sequel to the trilogy.
什麼
What?
他們通知我 不管有沒有我們都要做
They informed me they're gonna do it with or without us.
我以為他們不能這麼做
I thought they couldn't do that.
哦 他們可以
Oh, they can.
而且他們表達得很清楚
And they made it clear
如果我們不做他們就會終止合約
they'll kill our contract if we don't cooperate.
真的
Really?
我知道你說過對你來說已經結束了
I know you said the story was over for you,
但故事就是故事
but that's the thing about stories.
他們永遠不會真正結束 對嗎
They never really end, do they?
我們還是要講那個我們一直講的故事
We're still telling the same stories we've always told,
只是換個名字 換個面貌
just with different names, different faces
我不得不說 我有點激動
and I have to say I'm kind of excited.
經過這麼多年
After all these years,
再回到起點
to be going back to where it all started.
回到The Matrix
Back to The Matrix.
我已經和市場部談過了...
I've spoken to Marketing...
Tom
Tom?
怎麼
Yeah.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
沒事
Yeah.
你當時感覺如何
What were you feeling at that point?
我的感覺
What was I feeling?
我覺得要麼我又一次精神崩潰了
I felt either I'm having a mental breakdown again
要麼我就是活在一個電腦生成的現實裡
or I'm living inside a computergenerated reality
把我困住了
that has imprisoned me...
再一次
again.
沒有選擇啊
Not much of a choice.
沒有
No.
也許這不是那麼非黑即白
Maybe it's not as binary as that.
也許還有其他方法去理解發生了什麼
Maybe there are other ways to understand what happened.
是啊
Yeah.
Thomas 你是自殺未遂者
Thomas, you are a suicide survivor
在想像力上有超強的天賦
gifted with a powerful imagination.
這些事結合在一起
Those facts have combined
在你生活中創造出了危險的小說
to create dangerous fictions in your life.
昨天 你參加了一個會議
Yesterday, you walked into a meeting
和你的商業夥伴一起
with your business partner
他打了你一個措手不及
and he ambushed you,
要求你做出一個 你說過永遠不做的遊戲
demanding you make a game you said you would never make.
他剝奪了你的發言權
This attack effectively took away your voice.
他觸發了你在腦子裡反擊的想法
His violence triggered you and your mind fought back.
你以其人之道還治其人之身
You did to him what he was doing to you.
我們討論過在創傷治療中
We've talked about the value
適應憤怒情緒的價值
of adaptive anger in healing trauma.
但絕非重複你最初的崩潰
Far from suggesting a repeat of your initial breakdown,
我相信這段插曲
I believe this episode
顯示了一種良性的自我保護
demonstrates healthy selfprotection.
更重要的是 我記得這有多難
And more importantly, I remember how hard
讓你來分享這些事情
it was for you to share something like this.
這告訴我 我們已經比以前有了多少起色
Which tells me just how far we've come.
跟藥方再開點藥嗎
Do you need a refill on your prescription?
是啊
Yeah.
首先 我知道 我代表每個人說話
First of all, I know I speak for everyone
當我這麼說的時候 我非常非常激動
when I say that I'm so, so excited
能做這個遊戲 那真是個...
to be working on a game that was such a...
嗯 遊戲的革命者
well, game changer.
現在 在你面前的資料包裡
Now, the packet in front of you
有我們的焦點調研小組的研究
has our focus group research.
在裡面 你會找到分類
Inside, you'll find the breakdown
包括了品牌關聯的關鍵字
including keyword association with the brand.
前兩名是 創意 和 新鮮
The top two being "originality" and "fresh,"
我想最好是時刻把它們記在腦子裡
which I think are great things to keep in mind
當你開始著手《Matrix 4》工作的時候
as you begin working on Matrix 4.
誰知會不會有更多續作呢
And who knows how many more?
是什麼讓Matrix與眾不同 他搞亂你的大腦
What made Matrix different? It effed with your head.
切中要害
On point.
人們想要我們進到他們的灰色空間
People want us up in their grey space,
按下開關把他們的 我靠 點亮
switching their synaptic "WTF" light on.
是什麼讓Matrix與眾不同 他搞亂你的大腦
What made Matrix different? It effed with your head.
人們想要我們進到他們的灰色空間
People want us up in their grey space,
按下開關
switching their synaptic
把他們的 我靠 點亮
"What the hell is going on here?" light on.
《The Matrix》第一部電影評價最高 這裡是在故意調侃
我不喜歡第一部 就像你們中的一些人
I didn't love the first one, like some of you.
老實講 我簡直受不了
And, frankly, I've got zero tolerance
那些什麼複雜的筆記和攻略
for anything that requires a syllabus and a highlighter.
我喜歡我的遊戲夠大型 夠熱鬧 又夠傻瓜的
I like my games big, loud and dumb.
我們需要槍 很多槍
We need guns! Lots of guns.
Matrix意味著混亂
Matrix means mayhem.
盲目的行動不符合我們的品牌
Mindless action is not onbrand.
她說的對
She's right.
Matrix是精神高潮 是閃亮的哲學...
Matrix is mindporn. Philosophy in shiny...
-緊身皮衣 -對的
-tight PVC. -Yeah.
創意是新的 性感
Ideas are the new "sexy"
蒙蔽住現實遠比去實現夢想更加容易
很明顯The Matrix是關於...
Obviously The Matrix is about...
-...超越政治  -秘密法西斯主義
-...transpolitics. -Crypto-fascism.
這是用來比喻...
It's a metaphor...
...資本主義剝削
...of capitalist exploitation.
這不能是另一次重啟 翻新 反復...
This cannot be another reboot, retread, regurgitated...
為什麼不行 重啟也大賣啊
Why not? Reboots sell.
我們走太遠了 這裡 各位
We are so far down the wrong rabbit hole, here, people.
你對任何人提起Matrix... 你說Matrix...
You say Matrix to anyone... You say Matrix...
Matrix... Matrix... Matrix
Matrix... Matrix... Matrix...
...這他們就會想到這個
...this is what they see.
允許我總結一下我們的目標 就一個字
Allow me to sum up our goal in a single word.
子彈時間 子彈時間
Bullet time! Bullet time!
那是兩個字
That's two words.
我們需要新的 子彈時間
We need a new "bullet time"
我們需要再次革新遊戲
We need to revolutionize gaming again.
再次革新遊戲
Revolutionize gaming again!
午安 Tiff.
Afternoon, Tiff.
來杯烏什
The ushe?
Skroce 我要瘋了
You know what, Skroce? I'm going wild.
今天我要來杯可塔朵
I'll have a cortado today.
放飛自我吧
Fly that freak flag.
介意給我也來一杯那個嗎
Mind if I get that?
哦 嗨
Oh, hi.
嗨
Hi.
我記得想要一個家
I remember wanting a family,
那是因為
but was that because
這就是女人的本性嗎
that's what women are supposed to want?
你怎麼知道是你自己想要什麼的
How do you know if you want something yourself
還是你被成長環境灌輸成想要什麼的
or if your upbringing programmed you to want it?
嗯
Mmm.
我付給我分析師很多錢
I pay my analyst a lot of money
來為我回答這樣的問題
to answer such questions for me.
聰明
Smart.
我應該接受更多的治療
I should get more therapy
但老實說 我他媽太累了
but honestly, I'm too goddamn tired.
養小孩很累人 你懂嗎
Kids are exhausting, you know?
不懂 沒有過孩子
No. Never had kids.
哦 對的 我知道
Oh, right, I knew that.
對不起 我上網搜了你
Sorry. I googled you.
當一名世界著名的遊戲設計師什麼感覺
So, what's it like being a worldfamous game designer?
-一定很棒吧...-呃
-Must be amazing. -Uh...
花了好多時間
A lot of hours.
有時的確很棒
Sometimes it is amazing.
但大多數時候...
Most times...
我也不知道
I don't know.
但是你做了The Matrix 連我都聽說過
But you made The Matrix. Even I've heard of that.
是啊 我們讓孩子們有點娛樂
Yeah. We kept some kids entertained.
那麼 值得嗎
So, worth it?
我能問個關於你遊戲的問題嗎
Can I ask something about your game?
當然
Sure.
遊戲主角是你根據自己創作的嗎
Did you base your main character on yourself?
他身上有很多我
There is a lot of me in him.
也許有點太多了
Maybe a little too much.
我能問你點別的嗎
Can I ask you something else?
請
Please.
你的遊戲裡有一名女性
There's a woman in your game.
Trinity
Trinity.
她身上也有些奇怪的巧合 對吧
Which is a weird coincidence also, right?
天啊 是的
God, yeah.
我喜歡她
I like her.
-我喜歡Trinity -啊
-I like Trinity. -Ah.
我發現了她的杜卡迪摩托
And I dig her Ducati.
真巧 我也熱愛摩托車
Another coincidence. I love motorcycles.
我的朋友Kush和我 是造摩托車的
My friend Kush and I actually build them.
真的
Really?
你有你的分析師 我有我的摩托車
You have your analyst, I have my bikes.
我看你遊戲的圖片 看到Trinity
So, I was looking at images from your game. At Trinity.
我給Chad看了一下
Well, I showed Chad a scene,
我問他 你覺得怎麼樣
and I was like, "So, what do you think?"
但直到我給他解釋他才明白
He didn't get it until I said,
你不覺得她長得像我嗎
"Don't you think she looks like me?"
你知道他什麼反應嗎
You know what he did?
他笑了
He laughed.
我也笑了 就像在開玩笑一樣
And I laughed too, like it was a joke.
畢竟這怎麼可能呢 對吧
How could it not be, right?
我其實很生氣
Made me so angry.
我恨自己笑了
I hated myself for laughing.
我真想狠狠地踢他一腳
I wanted to kick him so hard.
也不能太狠
Not too hard.
夠把他的下巴打斷就行
Maybe just hard enough to break his jaw off.
現在 你可能後悔
And right now, you're probably regretting
跟我坐在一起了
sitting down with me.
這是我長時間以來做的最好的一件事了
This is the best thing I've done in a long time.
我聽個電話
I have to take this.
嗨 我是Tiff
Hi, this is Tiff.
哦 天哪 不
Oh, God, no.
我馬上到
I'll be right there.
我的小兒子 把樂高玩具塞進他鼻子裡了
My, uh, youngest stuck a Lego up his nose.
哦
Oh.
我得走了
I gotta go.
我希望能再次見到你
I hope I see you again.
現接到報告
There has been a report
有緊急情況
of an emergency.
請冷靜地走到最近的出口
Proceed calmly to the nearest exit
並立即離開大樓
and leave the building immediately.
發生什麼事
What's going on?
我們可能被某個小孩子惡作劇了
We probably just got swatted by some 14yearold.
對 有人對最新的更新很生氣
Yeah, someone pissed about the latest update.
或者他們只是沒事找事
Or they're just a dick.
請走到出口處 大樓正在疏散
Please move to the exits. Building's being evacuated.
有新消息 未知來源
嗨 Neo
如果想得到你那些疑問的答案 就去走廊盡頭的房間
現在就去
你是誰
你知道是誰
先生 這邊
Sir, this way.
Jude
Jude?
Jude!
終於
At last.
啊
Ah.
我不是很有把握
I wasn't too sure about the callback,
但是 你知道 很難抗拒啊
but, you know, it was hard to resist.
什麼
What?
Morpheus 在窗前出現
Morpheus Uno. Reveal at the window.
電閃 雷鳴 還有演出
Lightning, thunder and theater.
終於
At last.
這麼多年以後 我來了
All these years later, here's me,
漫步走出廁所隔間
strolling out of a toilet stall.
悲劇還是鬧劇
Tragedy or farce?
我認識你
I know you.
可不是天天都能遇到你的造物主
Not every day you meet your maker.
這不可能
This can't be happening.
哦 絕對發生了
Oh, most definitely is.
你不可能是我編寫的角色
You can't be a character I coded.
100%天然
100% natural.
怎麼可能
How?
所有你需要的解釋
All the explanation you need.
哦
Oh.
不
No.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
哇哇哇  不 是什麼意思
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What do you mean, "no"?
你就是想這樣 你才這樣做的 這是你的主意
You wanted this, you did this. This was your idea.
那只是個測試 是個實驗
It was a test. An experiment.
實驗
An experiment?
你把我放在一個狹小模態裡
You put me in a tinyass Modal,
讓我撞到
left me to bang my head till
頭破血流 就為了找到你
I nearly lost my shit searching for you
就為了一個實驗
as an experiment.
出口正在崩潰 他還沒有吃藥
The exit's breaking down. He hasn't taken the pill.
什麼 沒時間了
What? There's no time.
我知道 我知道 他正在醞釀
I know, I know. He's having a moment.
他知道黑進那面鏡子有多難嘛
Does he know how hard it was to hack that mirror?
還開著
Still open.
這..這不可能是真的
This... This can't be real.
目標鎖定 我們抓到他了
Target acquired. We got him.
這沒有發生過
This isn't happening.
這是我的幻想 這是我的幻想
It's in my mind. It's in my mind.
嘿 你站住 別動
Hey, you! Stop! Hold it!
這不可能
This can't be happening.
停止 不許動
Freeze! Don't move!
Neo
Neo!
哦 天哪
Oh, my God!
Neo
Neo!
Anderson先生
Mr. Anderson!
不
No!
不可能
It can't be.
我想你了
I've missed you.
這是我的想像
It's in my mind.
你能聽見我說話嗎 Thomas
Can you hear me, Thomas?
跟著我的聲音
Follow my voice.
用你的指尖去感觸 能感受到什麼
Feel the tips of your fingers. What are they touching?
鈴鐺
The bell.
你聽到鈴聲了嗎
Do you hear the bell?
你記得發生了什麼嗎 你是怎麼到這來
Do you remember what happened? How you got here?
你一定是走來的
You must have walked.
黑貓的名字叫做 Deja-Vu 意為:似曾相識
我聽到黑貓在外面的聲音
I heard Deja Vu outside,
我打開門 你就在那裡
opened my door, and there you were.
你要談談嗎
You feel like you can talk about it?
當我們開始治療的時候
When we started working together,
你失去了辨別
you had lost your capacity
現實和幻想的能力
to discern reality from fiction.
你嘗試從樓上跳下來後 找到了我
You came to me after trying to jump off a building.
你說你想飛走
You said you wanted to fly away.
我們取得了很多進展
We have made a lot of progress since then,
但你現在看來發病的特別嚴重
but you seem particularly triggered right now.
你能告訴我嗎是怎麼開始的嗎
Can you tell me how it started?
他給我發短信了
He texted me.
誰
Who?
Morpheus
Morpheus.
啊
Ah.
他回來了
So, he's back.
實際也並不完全是他
It wasn't actually him.
那是我給模態編寫的一段程式
It was a program I coded for a Modal.
而這個 模態 裡的Morpheus
And this "Modal," Morpheus,
來幫你逃離
came to help you escape
被稱作The Matrix的虛擬實境
from a virtual reality called The Matrix.
我瘋了嗎
Am I crazy?
我們在這裡不用那個詞
We don't use that word in here.
我該用什麼詞
What word should I use?
什麼詞能解釋發生在我身上的事
What word explains what is happening to me?
我能看看短信嗎
Can I see the texts?
被刪掉了
They were erased.
如果開上我的車去你的辦公室
If we got in my car and drove to your office,
你認為在那裡能發現什麼
what do you think we'd find there?
沒有什麼
Nothing.
因為沒有攻擊
Because there was no attack.
沒有人被殺
No one was killed.
沒有人發短信
No one texted.
我的腦子編造了這一切
My mind made it all up.
我應該這麼說嗎
Is that what I'm supposed to say?
是你所相信的嗎
Is that what you believe?
感覺很真實
It felt real.
當然
Of course.
你的雄心壯志就是令遊戲變得
It was your great ambition to make a game
和現實一樣逼真
that was indistinguishable from reality.
為了實現這一目標
To achieve this goal,
你把自己生活中的元素變成遊戲中的劇情
you converted elements of your life into narrative.
你為了宣洩對你商業夥伴的憤怒
Your sublimated anger toward your business partner
讓他變成了你的死敵
cast him as your nemesis.
一位名叫Tiffany的已婚婦女
A married woman named Tiffany
變成了命中註定的 Trinity
became the "Trinity" of a doomed romance.
連我這隻你不喜歡的貓都編進了你的Matrix
Even your dislike of my cat made it into your Matrix.
這很正常
There's nothing wrong with that.
藝術家就是這樣
It's what artists do.
但當幻想危及我們或其他人
But it becomes a problem when fantasies
就成了一個問題
endanger us or other people.
我們不想讓任何人受傷
We don't want anyone to get hurt,
對嗎 Thomas
do we, Thomas?
嗨 Thomas  大家都叫我 Tiff
Hi, Thomas. Everyone calls me "Tiff"
-你是誰 -我叫Trinity
-Who are you? -My name is Trinity.
沒人能告訴你 你陷入愛河了
No one can tell you you're in love.
只有你自己知道 從頭到尾
You just know it, through and through.
從裡到外
Balls to bones.
你感覺到了嗎
You feel this?
我永遠不會放手
I'm never letting go.
你必須放開一切 Neo
You have to let it all go, Neo.
解放你的思想
Free your mind.
哈
Huh.
看起來很容易
Looks easy enough.
解放我的思想  操
"Free my mind" Shit.
好吧
Okay.
解放我的思想
Free my mind.
我飛起來...
I fly...
或者摔死
or I fall.
你他媽是誰啊
Who the hell are you?
你不會記得我的
You won't remember me,
但是很久以前 你改變了我的世界
but a long time ago, you changed my life
當你從另一個屋頂跳下去的時候
when you leapt off another roof.
那時候 我就像其他電池一樣
Back then, I was just like any other coppertop,
過著假裝的生活...
pretending my life...
直到我抬起頭 看見了你
until I looked up and I saw you.
那是另一個你 但是我看的到
It was a different you, but I saw
真正的你
the real you,
就在前一秒...
just a second before...
你跳了
you leapt.
而你從未摔下去
And you never fell.
是你黑進了我的模態
Are you the one that hacked my Modal?
是啊
Yeah.
那是Jude
That'll be Jude.
他不是你的朋友
He's not your friend.
他是個處理常式 用來控制你的
He's a handle, a program used to control you.
他正在來這裡的路上
He's on his way here,
帶著特工和他在一起來的
and he's bringing Agents with him.
Jude
Jude.
兄弟 我一整晚都在給你打電話
Bro, I've been calling you all night.
我們有個大問題
We have a major problemo.
你一個人嗎
Are you alone?
這問的有點色情啊 夥計
That's kind of a sexy question, dude.
他們看起來不像典型的特工
They don't look like typical Agents.
他們現在使用機器人 皮膚像正常人一樣
They use bots now, skinned as normal people,
這意味著它們無處不在
which means they're everywhere
你永遠不知道能信任誰
and you never know who to trust.
我為什麼要相信你
Why should I trust you?
因為如果他們打開那扇門 我們就會失去入侵通道
Because if they open that door, we lose our hack.
我會被抓住然後被殺
I will be caught and killed
你會被繼續
and you will be put right back
放回他們為你設計的迴圈機上
on that treadmill they designed for you,
就像上次你要跳樓逃脫時
just like they did the last time
他們所做的那樣
you tried to leap your way out.
我知道你為什麼讓你的模態開放
I know why you left your Modal open.
你需要其他人先救出Morpheus
You needed someone else to free Morpheus.
這樣才能通過他找到你
And it's because of him that we were able to get to you.
我知道這些 就像我知道
I know these things the same way
有一天我肯定會找到你
that I knew one day I would find you.
當找到你的時候 你一定會準備好
And that when I did, you would be ready for this.
《The Matrix》一中 Neo也是跟著一個帶兔子紋身的女人開始了冒險
如果你想知道真相 Neo
If you want the truth, Neo,
你必須跟著我
you're going to have to follow me.
好吧
Okay.
我們在哪裡 東京
Where are we? Tokyo.
移動的傳送門 讓我們更難被追蹤
A moving portal makes it harder to track us.
-Seq是最好的專家 -入口安全
-Seq is the best of them. -Portal's clean.
正在讀取我們的蹤跡
Reading our shadows.
我不記得有這些啊
I don't remember this.
我們也不必再跑到電話亭了
We don't have to run to phone booths anymore, either.
門在你的右邊
Door's on your right.
佈景和設定 對嗎
Set and setting, right?
哦 不
Oh, no.
全是關於佈景的
It's all about set
和設定
and setting.
我們第一次接觸如此失敗
After our first contact went so badly,
我們借用你過去的經歷
we thought elements from your past
也許能幫你放鬆 進入現狀
might help ease you into the present.
只要一點點懷舊
Nothing comforts anxiety like
更能緩解焦慮的了
a little nostalgia.
這是你遊戲的錄影
This is footage from your game.
時間總是在對抗我們
Time is always against us,
等等..等等..
etcetera, etcetera.
沒人能說明
No one can be told
Matrix是什麼 之類 之類...
what the Matrix is, blah, blah, blah.
你必須親眼看到才能相信
You gotta see it to believe it.
該起飛了
Time to fly.
等等
Wait.
如果這是真的
If this is real,
如果我沒有發瘋 這意味著
if I haven't lost my mind, does that mean
這些都發生過
this happened?
但如果真的發生了...
But if it did...
那麼我們都死了
then we died.
顯然不是
Obviously not.
為什麼機器讓你活著
Why the Machines kept you alive
為什麼大費周折把你藏起來
and why they went to such lengths to hide you
這些問題我們都沒有答案
are questions we don't have answers to.
把我藏起來
Hide me?
我一直在一家公司開發一個就叫The Matrix的遊戲
I've been at a company making a game called The Matrix.
看起來他們沒試圖隱藏任何東西
Doesn't seem like they were trying to hide anything.
我們一直追蹤那家公司多年
We've been tracking that company for years.
我們篩選了所找到的每一個Thomas Anderson
We screened every Thomas Anderson we found.
我們沒想到的是
What we didn't understand
DSI Digital Self Image 數字自我映射
他們能夠改變你的DSI
was that they could alter your DSI.
培養倉生成了你的數字自我映射
Pods generate your digital selfimage
一個叫 外表 的顯示系統
through a feedback system called Semblance.
就生成了你所看到的自己
This is how you look to yourself.
通過某種方法他們能改變你的DSI循環
Somehow they were able to alter your DSI loop.
這是其他人看到的你
This is how everyone else sees you.
二十年
Twenty years?
為什麼花了二十年才找到我
Why did it take 20 years to find me?
遠不止20年
It took a lot longer than that.
已經過去六十多年了 自從你和Trinity
It's been over 60 years since you and Trinity
飛到機器城市
flew to one of the Machine Cities.
什麼
What?
有許多事我們都還不知道
There's so much we don't know.
比如為什麼你幾乎沒有變老
Like why you've barely aged,
或者他們改變了你的DSI多少次
or how many times they've altered your DSI.
但是據我們所知
But based on what we do know,
似乎沒人能找到你
it appears no one found you
是因為你不想被找到
because you didn't want to be found.
-那不是真的 -也許吧
-That's not true. -Maybe it isn't.
你失蹤的傳言
Maybe there's no foundation
可能毫無根據
to the rumors that you disappeared,
是因為你從一開始
because you were working
就和機器打交道
with the Machines from the beginning.
Morpheus 閉嘴
Morpheus, stop.
我想說的是 現在是時候
All I'm saying is this is the moment
讓你給我們展示什麼是真實
for you to show us what is real.
如果你想出去
If you want out,
你就要吃下藥丸
you'll take this pill.
但如果你屬於這裡
But if you are where you belong,
你可以選擇這個
you can go back to this.
日復一日
Every day.
不斷重複 直到永遠
Over and over forever.
操
Fuck.
保持回路緊密
Keep the loop tight.
Cybebe需要那個發電塔位置
Cybebe needs that tower pin.
我收到信號了 很微弱
I got a signal. It's faint.
這絕對是離線的
It's definitely offgrid.
艦長 我追蹤到一大堆奇怪東西
Captain. I'm tracking a whole lot of weird.
什麼  這是某種移植
What? It's some kind of graft.
Thomas
Thomas?
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
哦 不
Oh, no.
-我們被找到了 -他們怎麼找到我們的
-We got company. -How'd they find us?
Thomas 這些都不是真的
Thomas, none of this is real.
你正在嚴重的精神病發作中
You are in the midst of a serious psychotic break.
Lexy  差不多了
Lexy? Almost there.
Thomas
Thomas?
Thomas 拜託 這不是遊戲
Thomas, please. This is not a game.
摸摸我的手
Feel my hand.
這是真實的
This is what is real.
跟我走
Stay with me.
不 不
No. No.
跟我走
Stay with me.
Neo
Neo!
Morpheus
Morpheus!
走 走 走
Let's go, let's go!
-機器人正在被啟動 -這是一群
-Bots are being activated. -It's a swarm.
來吧
Come on!
我在洗手間黑了個出口 快點
I got a hack in the bathroom. Hurry!
好
Yes.
快來
Come on!
Seq 在哪裡
Seq, where?
-那面鏡子 -什麼
-That mirror. -What?
-我們鑽不進去 -你必須鑽進去
-We'll never fit. -You gotta fit,
因為這列車上我找不到其他出路了
'cause I don't have another way off this train.
哇哇哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
不不不
No, no, no.
想想 透視
Think "perspective"
你離的越近 它變的越大
Closer you are, bigger it gets.
好吧 來吧
Okay, come on.
進去吧
In you go.
Trinity
Trinity.
不!
No!
歡迎回到現實世界
Welcome back to the real world.
Trinity
Trinity.
-怎麼了 醫生 -他的重要器官
-What's up, Doc? -His vital systems
經過了精心維護
have been meticulously maintained,
但是看起來不太好
but it doesn't look good.
-他不行了 -冷啟動能把他救過來
-We're losing him. -Cold boot could shock him.
做吧
Do it.
我記得這個
I remember this.
結構
The Construct.
介於萬物
In between everything
與空白之間
and nothing.
歡迎來到我的寓所
Welcome to the Crib.
我一直在飛船網路中...
I've been chilling here in the ship network...
了解你的一切
learning all about you.
還有我的
And me.
小心 這會讓你上隱
Careful. It'll do your head in.
記憶會不會變得不那麼真實了
Are memories turned into fiction any less real?
記憶中的現實 只是幻想嗎
Is reality based in memory nothing but fiction?
至於我扮演的角色 我最好的猜測
As to my role in all this, my best guess
是你把我編寫成
is that you wrote me
所以在Neo寫的模態中Morpheus一人分飾兩角 Morpheus和Smith
用一種演算法映射出兩種不同的力量
as an algorithmic reflection of two forces
好促使你成為真正的你
that helped you become you,
Morpheus和Smith特工
Morpheus and Agent Smith.
一整套連續
A combo pack
逆向程式設計的組合 那真是...
of counterprogramming that was...
這麼說吧 多少有些瘋狂
Let's just say, more than a little bit crazymaking.
但它成功了 因為我們就在這裡
But it worked because here we are.
但是 壞消息
Now, for the bad news.
你的大腦這些年來已經對Matrix
Your brain is hooked on this shit
強行灌輸的鬼東西成癮了
the Matrix has been forcefeeding you for years.
非常嚴重的上癮
Hooked bad.
你會有嚴重戒斷症狀
You're going through major withdrawals.
醫療AI認為你的生存幾率極低
Docbots are giving you crap odds for surviving.
但是 他們不像我那樣了解你
But, see, they don't know you like I do.
我知道你最需要什麼
I know exactly what you need.
你開玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding.
沒啊
Uhuh.
不開玩笑
No joke.
這可以成為你新生的第一天
Could be this is the first day of the rest of your life.
但你想要新生
But if you want it...
你就得為這戰鬥
you gotta fight for it.
不 我不想戰鬥了
No. I'm done fighting.
真的
Are you?
他媽的 在做什麼
What the hell is he doing?
不錯 他們把你調教的很好
Oh, yeah. They taught you good.
讓你相信你只配呆在他們的世界
Made you believe their world was all you deserved.
但在你的內心知道這是個謊言
But some part of you knew that was a lie.
你還記得什麼是真實
Some part of you remembered what was real.
你並不了解我
You don't know me.
不嗎
No?
嗚
Ooh.
我了解你 因為我知道
I know you, because I know
有件事是你依然在乎的
the only thing that still matters to you.
我知道你此時此刻依然在奮戰的原因
I know it's why you're here, why you're still fighting
也知道你為何永不放棄
and why you will never give up.
來吧 Neo
Come on, Neo!
到時候了
This is it.
這就是你最後的機會了
This is your last chance.
你得為你那該死的性命而戰
You gotta fight for your goddamn life
如果你還想再見Trinity的話
if you want to see Trinity again.
來呀Neo 為她而戰
Come on, Neo! Fight for her!
-見鬼 -為她而戰
-Holy shit. -Fight for her!
-嗨 -嗨
-Hey. -Hey.
我幫你……
Mind if I...
你還好嗎
How are you doing?
如果這個插頭是真的
If this plug is actually real,
這意味看他們將我的人生
that means they took my life...
變成了電子遊戲
and turned it into a video game.
我好不好
How am I doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
我甚至都不知道該怎麼知道
I don't even know how to know.
就這樣了 對嗎
That's it, isn't it?
如果我們不知道什麼是真實的...
If we don't know what's real...
我們就無從抵抗
we can't resist.
他們奪走的你的故事
They took your story,
對很多人而言
something that meant
很多像我這樣的人而言很重要
so much to people like me,
但是他們把它變的無足輕重
and turned it into something trivial.
這就是Matrix的做法
That's what the Matrix does.
它們武器化每個思想
It weaponizes every idea.
每個夢想
Every dream.
每件對我們重要的事
Everything that's important to us.
埋藏在電子遊戲裡面
Where better to bury truth than inside something
更適合用來掩蓋真相的
as ordinary as a video game?
你語氣很像先知
That sounds like the Oracle.
我聽說了很多關於她的事
Heard so much about her.
在我被解放前她就不在了
She was gone before I was free.
不在了
Gone?
當現在這個新版本Matrix上線的時候
When this new version of the Matrix was uploaded,
進行了一次大清除
there was a purge.
他們承諾要和平 卻對我們進行了清除
They promised peace and they gave us purge.
不
No.
不 的確和平了
No, there was peace.
你實現了和平 這改變了一切
You made it possible, and it changed everything.
可我沒覺得有什麼改變
Doesn't feel like it changed anything.
Matrix還是一樣甚至更差了
The Matrix is the same or worse.
我又回到了起點
And I'm back where I started.
就好像我做的一切
It feels like everything I did,
我們所做的一切...
everything we did...
...都沒什麼用
...like none of it mattered.
一切都是有用的
All of it mattered.
我帶你看看
I can show you.
Mnemosyne 記憶女神 希臘神話裡掌管記憶、語言、文字的女神 十二泰坦之一
這都是我的船員
This is my crew.
我們的接線員 Seq
Our operator, Seq.
Sequoia 但是每個人都叫我Seq
Sequoia. But everybody calls me Seq.
幸會
Nice to meet you.
我爸喜歡紅杉
Dad loved redwoods.
當他逃離Matrix時
When he escaped the Matrix
發現紅杉已經絕種了
and found out they no longer existed,
差點活不下去
it almost killed him.
還好他遇到了我媽
Lucky, he met Mom
我就這麼來了
and here I am.
這是Lexy Berg和Ellster
This is Lexy, Berg and Ellster.
嗨
Hi.
你認識我祖父 Roland艦長
You knew my grandfather, Captain Roland.
Roland是你的祖父
Roland was your grandfather?
他總是開玩笑
He always laughed,
說他從來沒有相信過你
joking how he never believed in you.
但是 私下裡他說
But, in private, he said that
你再一次解放了他的思想
you freed his mind a second time.
呃 不敢說是你的粉絲
Uh, not to fanboy out here,
但此時此刻我真太激動了
but this is kind of a huge moment for me.
Berg是我們的常駐 Neo學家
Berg is our resident Neoologist.
什麼學家
A what?
有很多人就像我一樣
There's a lot of people out there like me
非常癡迷於你的生平
who are a little bit obsessed with your life.
如果有他在
I would never have recognized
我根本認不出你的模態
your Modal if it weren't for him.
等你輕鬆點了
Whenever you're feeling up for it,
我有數不清的問題要問
I've got, like, a million questions.
我也是 先從它們開始吧
Me too. Starting with them.
沒關係
It's okay.
來見見他
Come meet him.
這是Cybebe
This is Cybebe.
那是Octacles
That's Octacles.
那是Lumin8
That's Lumin8.
機器站在我們這邊了嗎
Machines are on our side now?
它們是合成體
They are synthients.
比起 機器 他們更喜歡這麼稱呼自己
It's a word they prefer to "Machines"
你和合成體城市的接觸
Your contact with the Synthient City
對它們的世界產生了巨大影響
had a huge impact on their world.
這就是我的意思
That's what I meant.
你改變了
What you changed
沒人相信可以改變的事情...
that nobody believed could ever be changed.
改變了 我們這邊
The meaning of "our side"
Cybebe和Octacles冒了生命危險
Cybebe and Octacles risked their lives
幫你逃出來
to help get you out.
非常感謝
Thank you.
但是為什麼呢
But why?
並非所有人都渴望掌控
Not all seek to control.
正如並非所有人都渴望自由
Just as not all wish to be free.
那是什麼
What is that?
外部變形粒子編譯器 這可是很先進的
An exomorphicparticle codex. It's pretty new.
它讓程式能接觸到現實
It gives programs access to this world.
在一定範圍內
Within limits.
範圍只是人為的限制而已
Limits are the domain of the limited.
Morpheus
Morpheus.
非常感謝
Thank you.
這是我的榮幸
It was my honor.
哇哦
Wow.
這是怎麼運行的
How does it work?
順磁共振
Paramagnetic oscillation.
如果你需要
If you want,
我可以給你下載編譯器使用說明
I can download the codex manual for you.
-好啊 -下載曾經很有趣
-Sure. -Downloading used to be fun.
現在都是手冊和診斷了
Now it's all manuals and diagnostics.
我能問他們點問題嗎
Can I ask them something?
當你把我抽離的時候 那裡還有一個培養倉
When you unplugged me, there was another pod?
對 我們已經分析了數據
Yes. We've analyzed the data.
那可能是Trinity
It could be Trinity.
就是她
It's her.
我就知道我們會談到這個
I figured we were going to have this conversation.
你的所在地不是那種簡單沖出後就抓的到的地方
Look, you were not a typical flushandgrab.
你在一座奇怪的塔里
You were in this weird tower that Cybebe
連Cybebe都沒去過 她現在被流放了
had never accessed, and she's now exiled.
我們在你身上用了唯一的機會
We burned our one shot for you.
就算Trinity她想要被解放
Even if it were Trinity and she wanted to be free,
我們也不知道該怎麼做
we have no idea how to do it.
暫時的
Yet.
也沒人相信我們能找到他
Nobody believed we'd ever find him,
但我們做到了
but we did.
好吧
Okay.
我們 暫時 還不知道如何把她解放出來
We don't know how to get her out... yet.
艦長 我們快到安檢站了
Captain, we're approaching security clearance.
我們到了
We're here.
錫安
Zion?
請坐
Have a seat.
這是Hanno 我們艦隊中最好的駕駛員
This is Hanno. Best pilot in our fleet.
有不少合成體
Quite a few synthients
都開的比我要好
deserve that title before me.
記憶女神號 已完成安檢
Mnemosyne, you are cleared
可以著陸 歡迎回家
for landing. Welcome home.
謝謝你 控制中心
Thank you, Control.
嗯 我們就要撞到了
Um, we're about to crash.
將軍意識到我們
General realized we were
永遠贏不了那些哨兵 所以...
never going to beat the Sentinels, so...
我們只是變得更善於躲避他們了
we just got better at hiding from them.
歡迎來到Io
Welcome to Io.
Io
Io.
哇 那看起來像真的一樣
Wow. That looks real.
生化天幕
Biosky.
有點像是種太陽
Works kind of like grow lights.
這可比她說的複雜太多了
It's way more complex than that.
從地殼中抽出水分 結合空氣
It pulls water from the crust, hydronating the air.
平衡了生態系統和我們的程式調度週期
It balances the ECO and our SRI cycles.
另外...
Plus...
它看起來真的很美
it is pretty to look at.
這就不美了
As opposed to that.
我猜將軍給我們舉辦了一個歡迎會
I guess the general sent us a welcome party.
該死的
God damn.
真是你
It is you.
Niobe
Niobe?
多了幾條皺紋 少了幾顆牙齒
A few more wrinkles and a few less teeth,
但是卻還是沒料到
but wise enough to know I don't know anything.
我死也想不到會發生這事
I sure as shit never saw this coming.
我也沒想到
Neither did I.
我告訴過你他還活著
I told you he was alive.
艦長 你和你的船員禁飛了
Captain, you and your crew have been grounded.
將軍 請允許我解釋
General, if you'd just let me explain.
機制是為了保護所有人而制定的
The protocols are put in place for everyone's protection.
我很抱歉 這個機會千載難逢
I'm sorry. I saw an opportunity
我怕錯失了他
and I was afraid we'd lose him.
而且 將軍 大家已經等了太久了
But, General, people have been waiting for so long.
我們找到了The One
We found The One.
我不相信The One
I don't believe in The One.
從來不信
I never did.
是嗎
No?
我也不信
Me neither.
但是當時
But there was a time
你還是違反了議會的命令
when you trusted me with your ship,
讓我用了你的飛船
against the Council's orders.
世界已經改變了
The world was different then.
我們也改變了
We were different.
去碼頭報到
Report to the docks.
清洗乾淨記憶女神號
Scrub down the Mnemosyne.
移交你的授權碼
Transfer your access codes.
沒你的事了 艦長
You are done, Captain.
我們得談談
We need to talk.
當我第一次得到消息
When word first came
說可能真的找到你了...
that it actually might be you...
我沒想過這一刻會是什麼感覺
I didn't know how I would feel in this moment.
很高興能見到你的
It is nice to see you.
我也很高興能見到你
It's good to see you too.
《The Matrix》第一部電影中Neo喝過Dozer釀造的酒精 而那時酒精的主要用處是用來溶解油漆
比Dozer的脫漆劑好喝多了
A long way from Dozer's paint stripper.
是啊
Yes.
好多事都變了
A lot has changed.
也許除了你以外
Except maybe you.
你還記得這個嗎
You remember this?
很容易就會忘記有多少噪音
It's so easy to forget how much noise
被Matrix灌進你的腦袋裡
the Matrix pumps into your head
直到你拔掉插頭
until you unplug.
是啊
Yeah.
還有些也會產生一些噪音
Something else makes the same kind of noise.
佔據所有的事情
Takes over every damn thing,
就像Matrix一樣
just like the Matrix.
戰爭
War.
我就站在聖殿的街壘上
I stood at the barricade of the Temple.
盯著那些哨兵部隊
Staring at the army of Sentinels,
等著他們殺光我們所有人
waiting for them to kill every one of us.
但接下來 他們離開了
But then, they left.
他們說你救了我們
They said you saved us.
我不相信
I didn't believe it.
每天晚上我都會夢到攻擊警報
Every night I would dream of attack sirens.
但是
But then,
我會在這裡醒來...
I would wake up to this...
一片寂靜
silence.
我現在為此感到羞愧
I'm ashamed of it now.
我的悲觀持續了許久才讓我最終相信
My pessimism of how long it took me to believe
沒有戰爭的世界是存在的
a world without war was possible.
是你帶來的
You gave me that.
是你給所有人帶來的這份禮物
You gave that gift to us all.
並且繼續的開花結果
And it is the gift that continues to bear fruit.
過來扶我起來
Come help me get up.
一起去散散步
Let's take a walk.
哦 真漂亮
Oh! Beautiful.
這是Freya 植物學主任
This is Freya, head of botany.
這是Quillion 我們的首席數字生化學家
And this is Quillion, our lead digitologist.
我想我們的客人不需要多做介紹了吧
I presume our guest needs no introduction.
沒有東西可以超光速
Nothing travels faster than light,
除了八卦
except gossip.
歡迎來到花園 Neo
Welcome to the Garden, Neo.
草莓
A strawberry?
從Matrix得到的數位編碼
Using digital code from the Matrix,
我們還原了DNA序列
we retroconvert it into DNA sequences.
它們能在這裡種植
And they grow here?
在生化天幕下進行光合作用
It's not easy augmenting the genome
可是相當的不容易 但是...
to photosynthesize Biosky, but...
就快成功了
We're getting there.
來嘗嘗看
Go ahead. Try it.
還有更讓人興奮的藍莓
We're quite excited about the blueberries.
你還記得我們以前吃的東西嗎
You remember that shit we used to eat?
那股像生銹的爛泥
That slop that tasted like rust.
錫安可做不出這樣的東西
Zion could have never made something like this.
為什麼
Why?
因為我們需要合成體
Because we needed synthients
和像他這樣的DI
and DI like him.
錫安被困在了過去 困在了戰爭
Zion was stuck in the past. Stuck in war.
困在了自己的Matrix中
Stuck in a Matrix of its own.
他們相信不是你死就是我亡
They believed that it had to be us or them.
建造這座城市的 是我們
This city was built by us
還有他們
and them.
錫安後來怎麼樣了
What happened to Zion?
我一直在等你問這個問題
I've been waiting for you to ask that question.
所有麻煩從機器城市開始
All of the troubles started in the Machine Cities.
發電廠產能不足
Power plants were unable to produce enough energy.
資源短缺 產生暴亂
Nothing can breed violence like scarcity.
我們第一次看到
For the first time,
機器城市陷入內戰
we saw machines at war with one other.
我們從先知處得到消息 一股新勢力正在崛起
We got word from the Oracle of a new power rising.
那是我們最後一次收到她的消息
That was the last we heard from her.
Morpheus
Morpheus.
圍城之戰以後 他被一致推舉為
After the siege, he was elected unanimously.
理事會最高主席
High Chair of the Council.
哦 他可喜歡幹這個了
Oh, how he loved that.
但當傳出有新勢力開始蔓延時
But as rumors of this new power spread,
他無視了傳言
he ignored them.
他肯定你的所作所為已成定局
He was certain what you had done could not be undone.
所有這些人從來沒有停止相信奇跡
All of these people never stopped believing in miracles,
相信你
believing in you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我也不知道會發生這一切
How could I know this would happen?
當時我們什麼都不明白
We didn't understand all of it back then.
現在也一樣
No more than we do now.
我不是來這裡給你添麻煩的 Niobe
I didn't come here to cause you problems, Niobe,
但我需要你的幫助
but I need your help.
Trinity還活著.
Trinity is alive.
那麼就有問題了
Then there is another question.
他們為什麼讓她活著
Why did they keep her alive?
我回答不了
I can't answer that.
但如果我有機會能夠救她
But if there's a chance I can free her,
我必須一試
I have to try.
哪怕會危及到這座城市的每個人
Even if it means endangering everyone in this city?
抱歉 Neo
I'm sorry, Neo.
我不會讓錫安的悲劇在Io重演
I won't let what happened to Zion happen to Io.
我希望你能原諒我一個老人
I hope you'll forgive an old woman
你跟Sheperd先離開
for asking you to go with Sheperd, here,
直到我們對局勢
till we have better understanding
有更多的了解
of what's going on.
你要在我剛被解放後就把我關起來
You're going to imprison me after I just got free?
我知道這事看似不公平
I know it doesn't seem fair,
但變老這件事也挺不公平
but neither does growing old.
但我可沒對此抱怨
But you don't hear me complaining.
很抱歉
Sorry.
我從來沒見過活著的傳奇
I've never met a legend before.
Neo
Neo.
Sheperd
Sheperd.
簡直瘋了 你是真的
Crazy. You're real.
真的
"Real"
還是這詞
There's that word again.
人們經常談論過去的時光
People talk a lot about the old days.
關於你 病毒特工
About you, the viral Agent.
對錫安的圍城
The siege of Zion.
當時一切都好像很簡單
Everything was simpler back then.
人們想要自由
People wanted to be free.
現在就不一樣了
It's different now.
有時感覺 現在的人都放棄了
Sometimes it feels like people gave up.
感覺就像Matrix已經贏了一樣
Like the Matrix won.
你的房間
This is you.
我得問你一件事
And I gotta ask you one thing.
你真的能飛嗎
Is it true you could fly?
真酷
Cool.
Morpheus
Morpheus.
哦 將軍把你關在了長髮公主的塔
Oh. General stuck you in the Rapunzel tower.
風景不錯啊
On the upside, it's a nice view.
Bugs和其他人怎麼樣了
What happened to Bugs and the others?
他們應該是在用牙刷
They're supposed to be sterilizing the Mnemosyne
-刷洗記憶女神號  -應該是
-with a toothbrush. -"Supposed to be"?
好吧 他們正在準備
Well, I could tell you that they're standing by,
等候你作出的選擇
waiting for you to make the choice
是繼續溫順的被軟禁
to remain meekly incarcerated
還是破門闖出去救Trinity
or bust the hell out of here and go and find Trinity.
但其實沒得選
But that ain't a choice.
將軍 我們該怎麼辦
General, what should we do?
Bugs的思想獨立
Bugs has the same independence of mind
和她解放那天一樣
she had the day you freed her.
這不是獨立思想
This is not independence of mind.
這是叛變
It's mutiny.
沒事的小Be
Come on, 'Be.
我知道你不想把他關起來
I know how much you hated locking him up.
就像我知道你其實
Just like I know there's a part of you
看到他走了也鬆了一口氣
that's relieved now that he's gone.
我們拼了老命保護Io的安全
We've worked so hard to keep Io safe.
現在我很害怕
This scares me.
就是她
That's her.
在橋上
On the bridge.
找到她了
Got her.
外表 系統真夠噁心啊
It's sick how the Semblance works.
你看到她的身體 但是...
You see flashes of the real her, but...
從她的編碼來看...
the way she reads...
她完全接受了藍藥丸
Codewise, she's pure bluepill.
這是個棘手的問題 Neo 但還是得問
This is a tough question, Neo, but it has to be asked.
如果她在這裡很開心呢
What if she's happy where she is?
我以前的編碼呢
How did I read?
跟她一模一樣
Exactly like her.
帶我們去可廣播深度
Take us to broadcast depth.
謝謝你幫助我
Thank you for helping me.
我們大多數人都是因你而存在
Most of us are here because of you.
而且我也得承認
I also admit our only chance
要想走出將軍那個狗屋
to get out of the general's doghouse
就要找回你的功夫
is for you to find your mojo.
如果我不再是以前的我怎麼辦
What if I can't be what I once was?
那我們就都完蛋了
Then we're all fucked.
兩分鐘
Two minutes.
兩分鐘後廣播
Two minutes to broadcast.
從酒店房間進去
I slipped you in through a hotel room.
應該是安全的
Should be safe.
傳送門打開了
Portal's open.
倉庫是離她車庫最近的地方
Closest I could get you is the warehouse near her garage.
整個區域都是機器人
Whole zone's crawling with bots.
走吧
Let's go.
那麼 你覺得他怎麼樣
So, what do you think of him?
一開始我有點擔心 他年紀太大了
I was kinda worried at first because he's so much older.
鬍子 頭髮...哦
The beard, the hair... Oh.
-不過跟我很合適 -你這個白癡
-No, totally works for me. -You idiot.
我是說 The One 那件事
I mean "The One" thing.
你知道嗎 所有和他同船的人都死了
You know, everyone that shipped with him died.
哦 沒錯 他會把我們都害死 肯定的
Oh, yeah. He's gonna get us all killed, for sure.
還是意料之中啊
Predictable as ever.
Smith
Smith.
Smith 就是 那個 Smith
Smith? As in, "the" Smith?
這太瘋狂了
This is so insane.
他倆的傳說太多了
There's so many theories about the two of them
他們就站在那裡
and they're standing right there.
這個編碼太變態了
This code is freaky!
他像個特工 但又不是
He's like an Agent, but not.
理智一點
An appeal to reason.
你怎麼找到我們的
How did you find us?
你從來沒有欣賞我們的關係
You never appreciated our relationship.
不像分析師
Not like The Analyst.
-什麼 -我的醫生
-The what? -My doctor.
他把我們的連結 轉變成一條鎖鏈
He used our bond and turned it into a chain.
現在很明顯 對吧
It's so obvious once you see it, right?
但是整套編碼的更新真讓我大吃一驚
But this whole altered-code update really blew my mind.
我真不知道他是怎麼做到的
I still don't know how he did it.
你一個禿頂的書呆子
You, as a balding nerd.
像個小丑
Hilarious.
而我...
And me...
則更加完美
even more perfect.
也許這雙藍眼睛有點過頭了
Maybe a little too far on the piercing blue eyes.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
你想要什麼 Smith
What do you want, Smith?
我有很多夢想 Tom
I have such dreams, Tom.
偉大的夢想
Big dreams.
嗯 大部份都是極端暴力復仇的
Well, mostly just extremely violent revenge fantasies,
但為了實現我的夢想
but in order for me to pursue mine,
我勸你不要追求你的夢想
I need to dissuade you from pursuing yours.
嗯 聽起來很矛盾
Hmm. Sounds like conflict.
不能避免嗎
Inevitable?
不一定吧
Doesn't have to be.
只要你離Matrix遠遠的
All you have to do is stay out of the Matrix,
然後把醫生留給我
and leave the good doctor to me.
他是你的 我來是為了Trinity
You can have him. I'm here for Trinity.
這就是問題 Tom
That's the trouble, Tom.
他知道你會來的 我也知道
He knew you'd come, just like I did.
信我
Trust me.
你還沒有準備好對付他
You're not ready for him.
艦長 我從低頻區域讀到了傳送門
Captain, I'm reading portals from the lower frequencies.
我不會再讓他把皮帶套我脖子上
I won't have his leash on my neck again.
我找到了一些你的老熟人
I found some old acquaintances of yours.
Bugs
Bugs!
流亡者
Exiles.
我以為他們都被清除了
I thought they were all purged.
是你
You?
哦
Oh!
就是你
It is you!
[法語]
[French]
這麼多年 真不敢相信
All these years. I can't believe it.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
你偷走了我的生活
You stole my life!
[法語]
[French]
The Merv想說的是
What the Merv is trying to say,
他們和我有些類似
is that their situation is a little bit like mine.
他們要活 你就得死
To have their lives back, yours has to end.
殺了他
Kill him!
你毀了...
You ruined
所有讓我爽的東西
every suckmysilkyass thing!
我們曾經優雅
We had grace.
我們曾有風格
We had style!
我們曾經交流
We had conversation!
不是這樣...
Not this...
藝術 電影 書籍都更好
Art, films, books were all better!
原創很重要
Originality mattered!
你給我們弄出了 渣克臭臉書
You gave us FaceZuckersuck
氣候雞巴變暖 維琪狗屎百科
and Cockmeclimatey Wikipissandshit!
我還記得功夫
I still know kung fu.
Neo
Neo!
就像以前
Just like old times.
Neo
Neo.
我一直在想我們的事 Tom
I've been thinking about us, Tom.
看看事物的本質 就是二進制
Look how binary is the form, the nature of things.
1和0
Ones and zeros.
光明與黑暗
Light and dark.
選擇和放棄
Choice and its absence.
Anderson和Smith
Anderson and Smith.
你缺了點什麼 Tom
You've lost something, Tom.
你不是以前的你了
You're not what you used to be.
沒錯
It's true.
不錯 謝謝
Nice one. Thanks.
撐住 Neo
Come on, Neo.
艦長 你沒事吧
Captain. You okay?
沒事 Neo在哪裡
Yeah. Where's Neo?
Smith正要殺了他
Smith is killing him.
哪裡
Where?
真是抱歉啊 Tom
I feel bad about this, Tom.
畢竟是你讓我...
After all, you are the one who set me free...
重獲自由
again.
所以 你比任何人
So, you, more than anyone,
更明白我為什麼不能走回頭路
understands why I can't go back.
你早該聽我的
You should have listened to me.
現在你永遠也見不到她了
Now you'll never see her again.
那是什麼
What was that?
那是Neo
That was Neo.
魔力回來了
Mojo rising.
你沒事吧
You all right?
沒事
Yeah.
這會引發系統反應
It's gonna trigger a response.
我準備了幾個出口
I got multiple exits ready.
這事沒完
This is not over yet!
續集特輯外傳我都會回來
Our sequel franchise spinoff!
[法語]
[French]
我們得離開了
We should go.
我不能
I can't.
我必須和她談談
I have to talk to her.
Neo 那些流亡者比你還要古老
Neo, those Exiles were older than you,
我們差點搞不定
and we barely handled them.
你現在真想這麼做嗎
You really wanna do this now?
我是說...
I mean...
你糟透了
you look like shit.
哦 天哪 怎麼 怎麼回事
Oh, my God. What? What happened?
有點意外
An accident.
Kush 叫醫生
Kush! Call a doctor.
沒事
It's fine.
我時間不多
I don't have a lot of time.
我不知還能不能再見到你
I wasn't sure I'd see you again.
在我們交談後 我意識到...
After we spoke, I realized...
我的人生不是真正的人生
my life wasn't a life.
不知不覺 我就放棄了
At some point, I think I gave up
尋找現實
searching for something real.
等等
Wait.
出事了嗎
Something happened.
我去咖啡店找過你
I looked for you at the coffee shop.
我懷疑你是不是我想像出來的
I began to wonder if I imagined you.
然後昨晚我做了一個夢
And then last night I had a dream.
在夢中 你被警察包圍
In the dream, you were surrounded by police,
然後他們開始追我們
then they started chasing us.
-我們 -你和我一起騎著我的摩托
-Us? -You were on my bike with me.
結局呢
How did it end?
不好
Not good.
我也做過這種不只是夢的夢
I've had dreams that weren't just dreams.
你是說夢成真了
You mean a dream that came true?
終於 我們可以像成年人一樣談談了
Finally, we can talk like adults.
我討厭撒謊 真的 我特別累
I hate lying. I do. It exhausts me.
Tiff和我一直都在等著你...
Tiff and I have been waiting for you...
一直都在等
like, forever.
似曾相識 對吧
Deja vu, right?
哦 沒用 你敵不過時間
Oh, no use. You can't beat time.
倒帶速度比你眨眼還快
This rewind is happening faster than you can blink.
你給了我這個想法
You gave me the idea.
我總結一下我們的目標 就一個字
Allow me to sum up our goal in a single word.
子彈時刻
"Bullet time"
我知 有點諷刺
I know. Kind of ironic,
用你的力量反過來控制你
using the power that defined you to control you.
我一直密切關注著你
I kept such a close eye on you
但你還是找到了出路
and still you found a way out.
小聰明哈 用模態
Clever monkey, using that Modal.
我很樂觀
Call me an optimist,
這些可能都是好事
but this could all be for the best.
皮膚保養的還不錯啊
The skin's not looking too bad this time.
你聽到這些可能很難過
I know some of this will be difficult for you to hear,
畢竟你經歷了這麼多
after everything you went through.
痛苦和折磨
All that pain and suffering,
才明白世界不會因為就這樣結束
only to learn the world doesn't end when you do.
驚不驚喜
Surprise.
你死的時候我當時在場
I was there when you died.
我對自己說
I said to myself,
這是異常中的異常
"Here is the anomaly of anomalies"
多麼難得的機會
What an extraordinary opportunity.
首先 我要說服高層
First, I had to convince the Suits
讓我重建你們兩個的身體
to let me rebuild the two of you.
為什麼她 告訴你吧
Why her? Getting there.
別擔心 她聽不見
And don't worry, she can't hear me.
你倆復活的成本高的離譜
Resurrecting you both was crazy expensive.
就像裝修房子一樣
Like renovating a house.
兩倍的時間 兩倍的開支
Took twice as long, cost twice as much.
我以為你會很高興能復活
I thought you'd be happy to be alive again.
大錯特錯了
So wrong.
希望和絕望的編碼幾乎相同
Did you know hope and despair are nearly identical in code?
我們研究了很多年
We worked for years,
嘗試啟動你的源代碼
trying to activate your source code.
就在我要放棄的時候 我意識到...
I was about to give up, when I realized...
Trinity
Trinity.
...從來不是你一個人
...it was never just you.
作為單一個體 你們兩個都沒什麼價值
Alone, neither of you is of any particular value.
就像酸和鹼一樣
Like acids and bases,
當混合一起的時候你就變得很危險
you're dangerous when mixed together.
每次你們接觸後的模擬....
Every sim where you two bonded...
從沒好事
Let's just say bad things happened.
Neo
Neo!
不過 只要我能讓你們離得足夠近
However, as long as I managed to keep you close,
但又不要太近
but not too close,
我發現了不可思議的現象
I discovered something incredible.
我的前任特別熱愛精確
Now, my predecessor loved precision.
他的Matrix全是繁瑣的細節和方程
His Matrix was all fussy facts and equations.
他憎恨人類的思想
He hated the human mind.
所以他沒興趣去了解
So he never bothered to realize
你們並不那麼在乎現實
that you don't give a shit about facts.
一切都是虛構
It's all about fiction.
最重要的東西就在這
The only world that matters is the one in here.
而你們這些人都有各種瘋狂的想法
And you people believe the craziest shit.
為什麼
Why?
怎麼才能證明你的幻想是真實的
What validates and makes your fictions real?
是感覺
Feelings.
我介紹一下
Allow me.
Kush 處理常式終端之一
Kush, here, is one of my handlers.
他們到處都是
They're everywhere.
太痛苦了 複製特工到電池人身上
Such a pain, cloning Agents over a coppertop.
只是人口飽和得更快
Far more effective just to saturate a population.
意外之喜 機器人群模式爽死人
And, bonus, swarm mode is sick fun.
哦 幹得好
Ooh! Nicely done.
你有沒有奇怪為什麼老做噩夢
You ever wonder why you have nightmares?
為什麼你的大腦總是折磨你
Why your own brain tortures you?
實際上是我們幹的 讓你的輸出最大化
It's actually us, maximizing your output.
是這樣的
It works just like this.
哦 不 你能擋住子彈嗎
Oh, no! Can you stop the bullet?
再快一點就好了
If only you could move faster.
全靠感覺
Here's the thing about feelings.
感覺比事實更容易控制
They're so much easier to control than facts.
結果 在我的Matrix裡
Turns out, in my Matrix,
我們對你越差 越能操控你
the worse we treat you, the more we manipulate you,
你產生的能量越多
the more energy you produce.
簡直瘋了
It's nuts.
我不斷創下新紀錄
I've been setting productivity records
我接手以來 年年如此
every year since I took over.
最棒的是 零拒絕
And, the best part, zero resistance.
人們呆在他們的培養倉裡
People stay in their pods,
比豬呆在糞坑還開心
happier than pigs in shit.
這一切的關鍵
The key to it all?
你
You.
還有她
And her.
靜靜地嚮往著你沒有的東西
Quietly yearning for what you don't have,
又害怕失去你所擁有的一切
while dreading losing what you do.
對於99.9%的人類來說
For 99.9% of your race,
這就是現實
that is the definition of reality.
渴望和恐懼 寶貝
Desire and fear, baby.
給他們想要的 對吧
Just give the people what they want, right?
她是你唯一的歸宿 Thomas
She's the only home you have, Thomas.
事情變得無可挽回之前 回家吧
Come home before something terrible happens.
-Bugs -我聽到了
-Bugs! -I hear him.
Trinity
Trinity!
-你不應該那樣叫我 -抱歉
-You shouldn't call me that. -I'm sorry.
我得走了
I have to go.
但我會回來的
But I'll be back.
Neo 該走了
Neo! Time to go.
-哨兵 -更糟
-Sentinels? -Worse.
將軍命令我
General ordered me
照顧好這艘船
to look after the ship.
你跟蹤我們了
So you shadowed us?
檢查你的遠端掃描
Check your long-range scans.
烏賊正在這一帶搜索
Squids are combing this area.
他說對了
He's right.
你可以呆在這裡等死
You can stay here and die,
或者回來面對軍事法庭
or come back and face a court-martial.
你這叫做選擇
And you call that a choice?
Sheperd應該把你留給烏賊了
Sheperd should have left you to the Squids.
我太老了 不想坐在那開無聊的審判了
I'm too damn old to sit through some boringass trial.
Niobe 別怪Bugs
Niobe, don't blame Bugs.
你給我閉嘴
Do shut your mouth.
你要稱呼我將軍
Do address me as General.
還有不要拐走我的前艦長
And do not rob my excaptain of her agency,
儘管她總是
which she exercised with her own
那麼的短視和愚蠢
particular brand of shortsighted stupidity.
短視
Shortsighted?
你更關心的是種水果而不是解放自由意志
You care more about growing fruit than freeing minds.
我們不會爭論這個問題
We are not going to have this argument again.
這不是爭論 這是事實
It's not an argument. It's a fact.
你放棄了其他人類
You gave up on people.
我來告訴你 我要放棄什麼
I tell you what I'm going to give up on
是你
and it's you!
Sheperd 把她帶走
Sheperd, get her out of my sight!
將軍
General...
放下武器
Disarm!
Kujaku是我的朋友
Kujaku's a friend.
你好 朋友
Hello, friend.
好吧
Okay.
他
Him?
將軍
General.
謝謝你來看我
Thank you for seeing me.
我就在想 如果有誰
I figured if there was anyone
能夠理解這場亂局
who could make sense of this mess,
那就只有你了
it would be you.
你好 Neo
Hello, Neo.
我認識你
I know you.
我一直看著你呢
I tried to keep my eye on you.
為什麼
Why?
我們很久以前見過面
We met a long time ago.
早上好
Good morning.
Sati
Sati.
我父親知道我們還會再見
My father knew we'd meet again,
他希望再見時已經是美好時代
though he would have wished for happier circumstances.
他在你身上造成的疏忽
His inadvertent role in what happened to you
是他一生中最大的遺憾
was the greatest regret of his life.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我父親是總工程師
My father was the chief engineer
修建 畸變倉
at the Anomaleum.
什麼
The what?
我父親設計的復活艙
My father designed the resurrection pods
是Neo和Trinity被囚禁的地方
where Neo and Trinity were imprisoned.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你知道他發生了什麼事
You knew what happened to him?
你知道他和Trinity都還活著...
You knew that he and Trinity both were alive...
你都不告訴我
and you didn't tell me?
我也有幾次想告訴你 Niobe
There were times I doubted my decision, Niobe.
但Io需要你
But Io needed you.
這座城市需要你來建造
This city needed to be built
為了你和我們的人民
for your people as well as mine.
如果我把一切都告訴你
If I would have told you everything,
你將進退兩難
you would have had a very difficult choice to make.
我的朋友
My friends
讓我自己做選擇
let me make my own choices.
如果這是個錯誤
If it was a mistake,
我向你深切的道歉
you have my deepest apologies.
你現在來幹什麼
Why are you here now?
Neo的逃離破壞了Matrix的穩定
Neo's escape has destabilized the Matrix.
畸變倉現在只能從
The Anomaleum draws its current
Trinity一人身上提取電流
from Trinity alone now.
保險裝置已經觸發了
A failsafe has been triggered to reset
將Matrix重置到以前的版本
the Matrix back to the previous version.
但是分析師阻止了重置
But The Analyst halted the reset.
他說服了當局
He's convinced the authorities
你很快就自願返回
that you will soon return voluntarily.
他憑什麼這麼說
And why would he say that?
因為如果我不回去 他就會殺了Trinity
Because if I don't go back, he'll kill Trinity.
看你是願意重回艙內
Faced with returning to your pod
還是再次面對Trinity的死亡
or enduring Trinity's death again.
你會怎麼選擇 Neo
What would you choose, Neo?
我會回去
I'll go back.
嗯 分析師很了解你
Well, The Analyst knows you well,
但是這也讓他大意了
but that knowledge has made him incautious.
你逃走後
After you escaped,
他本應接受損失 轉移走Trinity
he should have accepted his losses and devacuated Trinity.
但那樣的話就不會有一個千載難逢的好機會
But that would have prevented this extraordinary opportunity
擺在我們面前了
that now exists before us.
幾小時前
A few hours ago,
沒有人可能說服我
no one would have been able to convince me
站在這裡 向你們解釋這樣一個
that I would be standing here, trying to explain a mission
瘋狂的任務
as crazy as this one.
你在做什麼
What are you doing?
-自願加入 -哦 不
-Volunteering. -Oh, no.
你是唯一一個我命令你必須去的艦長
You are the one captain that I am ordering to go.
現在你不用命令了 將軍
Now you don't have to order me, General,
因為我是自願的
'cause I'm volunteering.
我還需要兩個
I need two more.
你們都瘋了嗎
Are you out of your minds?
你們甚至都不知道那是什麼
You don't even know what it is.
將軍 我們了解你
General, we know you.
如果你說這很重要
If you say this is important,
沒人願意呆在家裡
none of us is choosing to stay home.
非常感謝
Thank you.
鼓起勇氣 祝你們好運
Knuckle up, and good luck.
關押Trinity的畸變倉
Trinity is held in the Anomaleum,
就藏在輸電塔的中間
which is in this transmission tower.
營救Neo時的通道已經被封住了
The passages used to rescue Neo are now sealed
還有一大群哨兵在輸電塔巡邏
and a legion of Sentinels patrols the tower.
因此 隱形將是首要的
So, stealth will be paramount.
只要我們不觸發警報
As long as we raise no alarms,
這就是最簡單的部分
this first part of the mission should be the easiest.
你是說穿過人類繁殖場
You mean crossing the Fetus Fields,
偷偷穿過整個發電廠
sneaking across an entire power plant,
攀登一座兩公里高的塔
climbing a two-kilometer tower
被成千上萬哨兵看守著
guarded by thousands of Sentinels?
是最簡單的部分
That's the easy part?
的確如此
Exactly so.
因為我們要做的 就是說服一個
Because all we have to do is convince someone
天天都這麼幹的人
who does this every day
把我們中的一個帶過去
to take one of us along.
在畸變倉下方50米
Fifty meters below the Anomaleum
有一個羊膜過濾器
is a stratum of amniotic filters.
在邊緣有個六邊形通風口
Hidden along this edge is a small hexagonal vent.
這個通風口為細胞調節器提供空氣
This vent feeds the air intake into the corpuscular modifier,
為Neo的倉的生物凝膠提供氧氣
which oxygenates the biogel used in Neo's pod.
我明白了
I get it.
用變形粒子從Neo的舊臍帶潛入進去
The exomorph slinkies up Neo's old umbilicus.
能出什麼差錯呢
What could go wrong?
一進去
Once inside,
Morpheus要使用操作員系統
Morpheus will use the System Operator
打開排水管並且關閉其中的粉碎器
to open the devacuator line and disengage the macerators.
拔掉Trinity身上的插頭前
In order to unplug Trinity's body,
她的意識還連接在Matrix
while her mind still remains connected to the Matrix,
所以我需要第二個人腦
I'm gonna need a second human brain
實施分流
to implement the bypass.
由於Neo必須和分析師在一起
And since Neo must be with The Analyst,
唯一足夠強大的可用大腦
the only available mind that's a nearenough match
是你的
is yours.
猜到了
Figures.
謝謝你 Cybebe
Thanks, Cybebe.
Trinity還是要吃下吃紅色藥丸嗎
Does Trinity still have to take the red pill?
Kujaku和我直接傳送
Since Kujaku and I are transferring
她的意識上船
her consciousness onto the ship,
嚴格來說不一定要吃
it's not strictly necessary.
但是她的選擇依然是最重要的
But what matters is that this is her choice.
如果她有疑惑或顧慮
Extracting a confused or an uncertain mind will,
可能會害死她
in all probability, kill her.
但即使她願意
But even if it is what she wants,
分析師不會派哨兵來阻止嗎
won't The Analyst just order the Sentinels to stop you?
他會的
He will.
但如果我的計劃成功了 就無所謂了
But if my plan works, it won't matter.
為什麼
Why?
因為我們早就提前跑了
Because we'll already be gone.
你的計劃如此周密
Somebody thinks this hard about a plan,
一定是另有原因吧
there has to be a reason why.
當我父親意識到
When my father realized
畸變倉會被如何利用
how the Anomaleum was going to be used,
他悄悄把設計圖交給了我
he covertly transferred the designs to me.
分析師發現了他的背叛
The Analyst discovered his betrayal
於是把我的父母都清除了
and had my parents purged.
如果不是有Kujaku我也會被殺掉
I would have been murdered too if it wasn't for Kujaku.
我天天都在悼念他們
Not a day goes by that I don't grieve them.
為這一天 我祈禱了很長很長時間
I've been praying for this day for a very long time.
我們馬上要廣播了
We're coming up on broadcast.
你應該知道 我能在這裡都是因為她
I thought you should know that I'm here because of her.
我想跟Trinity一樣無所畏懼
All I ever wanted was to be as fearless as Trinity.
但我看到了她在車庫裡的反應時 我...
But I saw how she reacted in the garage, and I...
在想我是不是錯了
You're wondering if I'm wrong.
如果我們太遲了
What if we're too late?
如果她不再是Trinity了
What if she's not Trinity anymore?
我從不相信我就是The One
I never believed I was The One.
但她相信
But she did.
她相信我
She believed in me.
現在輪到我相信她了
It's my turn to believe in her.
這裡開始變得棘手了
This is where it gets tricky.
你到底有沒有做過這樣的手術
Have you ever done an operation like this?
還沒有
Not yet.
我們開始吧
Here we go.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
我只想和她談談
All I want is to talk to her.
你是說Tiff嗎
Do you mean Tiff?
回來吧 你可以隨時和她聊天
Come back, and you can talk to her as often as you like.
不過我想 帥哥Chad
I mean, handsome Chad
可能會有點意見
may have something to say about it.
如果她說 這生活是她想要的
If she tells me this is what she wants,
你就贏了
you win.
真的
Really?
但是如果她想要的是我
But if she wants me,
那你就放我們走吧
then you'll let us go free.
我為什麼要做這麼蠢的事
And why would I do something as stupid as that?
我所在的飛船上 站滿了人 在你帶走我之前
Right now, I'm on a ship full of people who will unplug me
就會把我的插頭拔掉
before they'll let you take me back.
如果你想要這個Matrix
If you want this Matrix,
這是你唯一的機會
this is your only chance.
我怎麼知道他們不會拔掉你的插頭呢
But how do I know they won't unplug you anyway?
就像我怎麼知道你會不會放我們走一樣
Same way I know you'll let us walk out of here.
好吧
Okay.
我喜歡測試
I like tests.
就讓Tiff做決定
We'll let Tiff decide.
就這樣
That's it.
分流準備好了
Bypass is ready.
現在怎麼辦
Now what?
我們等吧
We wait.
大費周章來到
Doesn't it seem crazy to come all this way
難道真把她留在這裡
and leave her here?
我們必須尊重她的決定
We must abide by her decision.
如果她說不
And if she says no,
Neo會怎麼樣
what happens to Neo?
這一次
At this time,
是Neo一生中最重要的選擇
the most important choice of Neo's life
但不是由他做決定
is not his to make.
我夢中看到了這一幕
I saw this in my dream.
如果我是先知 也許我可以解釋一下
If I was the Oracle, maybe I could explain it.
先知
The Oracle.
你的遊戲裡那個
From your game?
這不是遊戲
It's not a game.
哦 天哪
Oh, God.
在你走後 我回家了
After you left, I went home
我玩了那個遊戲
and I played it.
我一直在想
I kept thinking,
為什麼這個劇情 像是一種記憶
why does this story feel like a memory?
我有種感覺
There's a part of me
像我一輩子都在等你
that feels like I have been waiting my whole life for you.
就像在說
And that part is like,
見鬼 你怎麼花了這麼長時間
"What the hell took you so long?"
這三言兩語說不清
I don't have an easy answer.
也許我害怕這個
Maybe I was afraid of this.
害怕可能發生的事
Afraid of what might happen.
害怕傷害到我唯一愛過的人
Afraid of hurting the only person I ever loved.
我希望我是你以為的那個人
I wish I was who you think I am.
但是看看我
But look at me.
我不可能是她
I can't be her.
-媽媽 -媽媽 來吧
-Mom! -Mom! Come on.
媽媽 Callie出事了
Mom! It's Callie.
這是現實嗎
Is this real?
你得和我們一起來
You have to come with us.
來吧 我們得走了
Come on, we gotta go.
Tiff 嘿 不管這裡發生什麼事了
Tiff, hey. Don't know what's going on here,
但終於找到了你
but I'm glad we found you.
-她被車撞了 -太瘋狂了
-She got hit by a car! -I know, it's crazy.
她追著你出來
She was chasing after you.
他們在包紮她的胳膊  我們得走了
They're casting her arm. We gotta go.
醫生說她會沒事的
Doctor said she's gonna be fine.
你要和我們一起去醫院
You have to come with us to the hospital.
太晚了
It's too late.
我明白
I understand.
-Tiff 來吧 我們走 -來吧
-Tiff, come on, let's go. -Come on.
怎麼回事
What's happening?
Neo錯了
Neo was wrong.
Tiffany
Tiffany.
Tiffany 你要跟我們一起走
Tiffany, you have to come with us.
Tiffany
Tiffany!
我希望你他媽的別這麼叫我
I wish you would fucking stop calling me that.
我討厭這名字
I hate that name.
我是Trinity
My name is Trinity
你最好把你的手拿開
and you better take your hands off of me.
Neo
Neo!
Trinity
Trinity!
我靠
Oh, shit.
把她帶出來 把她帶出來
Get her out. Get her out!
哎 呀 呀 真是一團糟
Aye-yi-yi, what a mess.
我承認錯了 我不應該施壓
I own that mistake. Shouldn't have pressed.
女人以前很容易控制的
Women used to be so easy to control.
你知道我不可能放你兩個走
You know there's no way I can let you two go free.
不可能的
Cannot happen.
所以 一切又變得似曾相識了
So, I guess it's deja vu all over again.
她死了
She dies
都是你害的
and it's all your fault.
謊話 謊話 謊話連篇
Lies, lies and more lies.
Smith
Smith?
這個世界變成了什麼樣子
What has the world come to
你連程式都不能信任了
when you can't even trust a program?
怎麼...
How...
Tom和我的共同點比你想像的要多
Tom and I have more in common than you know.
等他一出去
Once he got out, let's just say,
我就可以做我自己了
I was free to be me.
-耶 -Trinity
-Yeah! -Trinity?
準備好了嗎
You ready?
是的
Yeah.
大事不妙
Oh, no.
摧毀她 摧毀她
Destroy her. Destroy her!
不
No.
阻止他們
Stop them.
你以為這就完了
You think this is over?
封鎖 啟動機器人群
Lockdown. Initiate swarm.
出人意外的聯盟就此結束了
Here, our unexpected alliance ends.
你知道我們之間的區別嗎 Tom
You know the difference between us, Tom?
任何人都可能是你
Anyone could have been you.
而我一直都是任何人
Whereas I've always been anyone.
發生了什麼事
What just happened?
什麼
What?
哦 不 快走 快走
Oh, no! Move! Move!
趕快離開這裡
Get the hell out of there!
-有多糟 -糟透了
-How bad? -Like, all the bad.
好吧 這很糟糕
Yeah, this is bad.
你不會還能飛吧
I don't suppose you can still fly?
沒錯 還飛不起來
Yeah, that's not happening.
Neo 上來
Neo! Get on.
Calliope 帶上傷患
Calliope! Take the wounded!
其他人 我們和他們守一起
Everyone else, we stay with them!
-她怎麼樣 -生命跡象良好
-How is she? -Life signs are good.
她的信號很強 艦長
Her signal's strong, Captain.
幹得好 艦長
Well done, Captain.
我們需要的只剩下一點奇跡了
All we need is a miracle.
我討厭機器人
I hate bots.
-把我們弄出去 -我在努力
-Get us out of here! -I'm trying!
封鎖區正跟著我們 機器人群無處不在
The lockdown is tracking. Swarm is everywhere.
從沒見過這樣的事
Never seen anything like this.
Seq 那是什麼
Seq, what is that?
怎麼了
What's wrong?
你幹什麼...
What are you...
他正在把機器人變成炸彈
He's turning bots into bombs.
見鬼
Shit!
Lexy
Lexy?
Sheperd有麻煩了
Sheperd's in trouble.
把我送進去
Jack me in.
我可以讓你進去 但我不知道是否能讓你出來
I can get you in. I don't know if I can get you out.
不
No!
他們在做什麼
What are they doing?
把他們趕到殺戮地帶
Herding them into a kill zone.
艦長 你得趕快了
Captain, you gotta hurry.
撐住 Lex
Hang on, Lex.
Lexy
Lexy!
他們在這裡
There they are!
Morpheus
Morpheus!
Lex
Lex.
-Bugsy -好耶
-Bugsy. -Hell yeah!
Seq Neo在哪裡
Seq, where's Neo?
壞了 它們被困住了
It's bad. They're pinned.
去屋頂了
Heading to a roof.
結節顫動非常嚴重
Nodal fibrillation is critical.
如果我們不抽取 她會死
She'll die if we don't extract.
真美啊
It's so beautiful.
我記得這
I remember this.
我記得我們
I remember us.
我的夢在這裡結束了
My dream ended here.
我們回不去了
We can't go back.
不會的
We won't.
他們能成功跳過去嗎
Can they make the jump?
不是我啊
I'm not doing this.
是你嗎
Are you doing this?
回見
Bye.
好戲劇性啊
How dramatic.
Tiffany
"Tiffany"?
這只是一個私下的玩笑
It was a private joke.
娛樂一下 沒別的
An amusement, that's all.
娛樂 嗯...
An amusement? Hmm.
像這樣嗎
Kind of like that?
好吧 疼啊
Okay. Ow.
如果你這麼討厭這個名字
If you hated the name so much,
為啥你像個乖巧的小婊子一樣呆了這麼久
why did you heel like a good little bitch so long?
嗯 他自找的
Yeah. Definitely asked for that.
你就不能管管她嗎
Can't you control her?
這下是為了你利用小孩子
That was for using children.
我們有幾個問題
We have a few questions.
你試圖啟動保險裝置
You tried to activate the failsafe.
是高層試圖
The Suits tried.
很明顯 沒有了你的源代碼
Obviously, without control of your source code,
那是不可能的
I knew that was impossible.
那麼 為什麼高層沒有清除你
So, why haven't the Suits purged you?
因為我了解這個系統
Because I know the system.
我了解人類
I know human beings.
我了解你
And I know you.
現在 你對自己作所作為感到滿意
Right now, you're feeling good about what you've done.
應該的 你們贏了 太棒了
You should. It was a victory. Bravo.
這次又想怎樣
Now what?
你是來談判的嗎
You've come here to negotiate some kind of deal?
你覺得你手裡什麼牌都有
You think you hold all the cards,
因為你在這個世界裡隨心所欲
because you can do whatever you want in this world.
我想 去做吧
I say, go for it.
重塑一切 自己動手
Remake it. Knock yourselves out.
去天上畫個彩虹
Paint the sky with rainbows.
但問題是
But here's the thing.
小羔羊不會去任何地方
The sheeple aren't going anywhere.
他們喜歡我的世界
They like my world.
他們不想要多愁善感
They don't want this sentimentality.
他們不想要自由或權力
They don't want freedom or empowerment.
他們想要被控制
They want to be controlled.
他們渴望穩定帶來的安全感
They crave the comfort of certainty.
也就是說你們兩個 早晚會回到你們的培養倉
And that means you two, back in your pods,
獨自沉睡 像他們一樣
unconscious and alone, just like them.
我們不是來這裡談判的
We're not here to negotiate anything.
我們只是在重制你的世界
We were on our way to remake your world.
做點改變
Change a few things.
我有點喜歡
I kind of like
去天上畫彩虹的主意
the "paint the sky with rainbows" idea.
提醒人們自由意志能做什麼
Just remind people what a free mind can do.
我就忘了 很容易就忘記了
I forgot. It's easy to forget.
-他害的 -沒錯
-He makes it easy. -That, he does.
他應該考慮一下
Something he should think about.
在我們開始之前
Before we got started,
我們決定順道來謝謝你
we decided to stop by to say thank you.
你給了我們從沒想過可以擁有的東西
You gave us something we never thought we could have.
那是什麼
And what is that?
再來一次的機會
Another chance.
面對現實吧 電影已經過時了
Face reality, people. Movies are dead.
遊戲已經過時了
Games are dead.
好故事 過時了
Narrative? Dead.
媒體只剩下神經性反射
Media is nothing but neurotrigger response
和病毒式傳播
and viral conditioning.
等等 你們兩個在說什麼
Wait, what are you two talking about?
貓影片
Cat videos.
我們需要的是一系列影片
What we need is a series of videos
我們稱之為"貓客帝國"
that we call "The Catrix"